Wesley Anderson

🗣 Springfield, MA, United States 🛮 wes@wesanderson.net 🔭 wesanderson.net



I am a software engineer with years of experience with JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, and various frameworks. I am a co-creator of Chimera, which automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate synchronously on AWS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Chimera

2022 - present

Chimera (https://chimera-deploy.dev/ 2) automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate synchronously on AWS. It reduces the risk of introducing bugs that propagate through your microservice infrastructure by gradually shifting traffic to the canary while automating canary analysis.

- Designed initial workflow diagrams
- Created a toy microservice infrastructure on AWS to test Chimera
- Built an Express backend that Chimera uses to create, destroy, and configure AWS resources
- Implemented Chimera's ability to set up a CloudWatch agent that monitors metrics from the canary microservice
- · Developed Chimera's ability to automate threshold analysis on the canary using metrics from CloudWatch
- Co-presented a live tech talk about Chimera
- Wrote documentation for setting up and installing Chimera within its repository
- · Co-authored Chimera's technical case study

Software Engineer 2020 - 2022

- Requestotron: An RequestBin-like app -- NodeJS, PostgreSQL
- Rello: A Trello-like app -- NodeJS, React, MongoDB
- Todos: A task management web app -- NodeJS, JavaScript, SQLite

Researcher and Instructor of Philosophy & Logic, Various Institutes (including, Western New England University, Smith College, Konrad Lorenz Institute, and Arizona State University)

2016 - 2020

EDUCATION

Launch School, Software Engineering

2020 - 2021

Multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum emphasizing mastery of programming fundamentals and problem-solving -- launchschool.com/employers

Ph.D. in History and Philosophy of Science, Arizona State University

2011 - 2016



Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Go

Express, React, Next.js

Technologies

Docker, Git/GitHub, CI/CD, Container Orchestration, Nginx, Microservices

Frameworks

AWS: ECS, ECR, Fargate, App Mesh, CloudWatch, CloudFormation

1/1wes@wesanderson.net